[
    {
      "id": 1,
      "lab": "Lab-01",
      "title": "Scanning and Identifying Network Nodes",
      "scenario":"In this activity, you will use common network tools, such as local commands and the Nmap network mapper, to discover other hosts on the local network. Next, you will conduct a banner grabbing exercise to identify specific services on the hosts. Finally, you will use DNS tools to gather name resolution information. ",
      "objective":"This lab is desigined to test your understanding of and ability to apply appropriate tools to assess organizational security defined in CompTIA Security+ ",
      "url":"https://novnc.com/noVNC/vnc.html",
      "activities":[
        {
            "id":1,
            "title":"Identify the network configuration",
            "desciption":"Determine the configuration of the local host and its subnet, using tools such as ifconfig, ip, arp, netdiscover, and pathping. Run the scans from the KALI Linux VM.",
            "chekbox":true,
            "questions":[
                {
                   "id":1,
                   "question":"What is the IP address for the eth0 adapter of the Kali Linux virtual machine? (answer format: 1.2.3.4)",
                   "answer":"10.10.10.1",
                   "textbox":true
                },
                {
                    "id":2,
                    "question":"What is the IP address of the router? (format 1.2.3.4)",
                    "answer":"10.10.10.1",
                    "textbox":true
                },
                {
                    "id":3,
                    "question":"What is the IP address for the DC1.corp.515support.com virtual machine? (format 1.2.3.4)",
                    "answer":"10.10.10.1",
                    "textbox":true
                },
                {
                    "id":4,
                    "question":"How many hosts were found by netdiscover?",
                    "answer":"4",
                    "textbox":true
                },
                {
                    "id":5,
                    "question":"What is the IP address for the DC1 virtual machine?",
                    "answer":"10.10.10.1",
                    "textbox":true
                },
                {
                    "id":6,
                    "question":"What percentage of packets were lost during this test? (Reply with values such as 0%, 50%, 100%, etc)",
                    "answer":"20%",
                    "textbox":true
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "id":2,
            "title":"Use nmap to discover hosts",
            "desciption":"From a penetration tester or threat actor perspective, network reconnaissance will typically aim to discover the following.",
            "chekbox":true,
            "questions":[
                {
                   "id":1,
                   "question":"What port is open on the virtual machine? (443/tcp, 22/tcp, 80/tcp, 53/udp, 161/udp)",
                   "answer":"22/tcp",
                   "textbox":true
                },
                {
                    "id":2,
                    "question":"What services are running on this virtual machine (the router)? (Email and file transfer services, SSH and web services, SSH and DNS services, Web and email services) ",
                    "answer":"SSH and web services",
                    "textbox":true
                },
                {
                    "id":3,
                    "question":"What operating system is running on the 10.1.0.254 host? (Linux, Windows 10, macOS, Windows Server, MS-DOS)",
                    "answer":"Linux",
                    "textbox":true
                },
                {
                    "id":4,
                    "question":"Which server is configured as an email server? (Hint: you'll need to look for the default SMTP port number in the 'Ports used' field of each host) (PC1, LX1, MS1, RT1-Internal, DC1)",
                    "answer":"DC1",
                    "textbox":true
                }
            ]
        }
      ]
    }
  ]